Lorenzo Dandrea

1755 Juliet Ave St. Paul, Minnesota 55105

Github link: https://github.com/baronvontoby

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a self described technology enthusiast and hobbyist who enjoys spending time learning and making applications. Now I have turned this hobby and passion into a career and have taken the next steps by attending a coding bootcamp through the University of Minnesota learning full stack web development. This experience has prepared me to tackle end to end programming, from MongoDB and SQL database creation and deployment to utilizing react.js and JavaScript for front end functionality. The intense process of the bootcamp has prepared me to not only deliver quality work but learn quickly and find answers efficiently on any new technologies that might be necessary. With my background in customer relationships, communication and teamwork, I am able to work well in a team structure while also maintaining an independent work ethic and managing my time efficiently.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota

Full Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp, Saint Paul, Minnesota

April 2019 - July 2019

email:lgdandrea4@gmail.com

cell: 651-785-3774

Languages learned: MySQL, JavaScript, Java, HTML, CSS,

Skills: MERN Stack (Express.js, Node.js, React.js, MongoDB), Heroku, JQuery, Git, GitHub, Firebase, CSS

Frameworks (Bootstrap, Materialize)

Saint Mary's University of Minnesota, Winona, Minnesota

Graduated May 2010

Major: History

Minor: Political Science

PROJECTS

Pick Up Game Project (PUGS), Saint Paul, Minnesota

June 2019 - Present

- Undertook a complete reboot of the front end functionality of the application utilizing REACT.js and moving away from JQuery
- Lead a team of 3 developers that turned the application into a SPA utilizing REACT
- Created a web application that allows users to socially interact and find like minded people through pick up games.
- Worked primarily on the back end Javascript routing, middleware handling and database implementation.
- Due to the smaller team I was also responsible for front end Javascript DOM manipulation. Looking to reincorporate React.js as we move forward for a more responsive application.
- Worked on the user authentication team, utilizing Passport and also all external API calls using AJAX.
- Developed a unique system, using the Reflect.OwnKeys method that overcomes an Object Null issue that was
 happening on our server side code that allowed me to successfully pass JSON from the DOM to my database utilizing
 Sequelize.

- Took over project manager duties implementing daily Stand Ups to make sure we reached MVP within the given timeframe and also managed all pull and merge issues.
- The project runs on my Express Server and we use Node to serve it.
- I built our database utilizing MySQL and Sequelize to create tables and manage queries.

WORK HISTORY

Northern Widget LLC, Partner/Sales, Saint Paul, Minnesota

January 2010- Present

- Began a tech startup company focused on scientific data instruments
- Taking initiative to bring a product successfully to market from the ground up
- Successfully created and implemented the invoicing software and processed inventory for initial orders
- Self-starter requiring time management skills, customer relationship building and money management

Imagine IT Inc, Account Executive, Bloomington, Minnesota

April 2018- March 2019

- Worked closely with ownership to roll out new Hubspot platform to increase inbound marketing efforts
- Cold called potential prospects and qualified opportunities
- Attended and managed trade show booths
- Joined up with several networking groups that involved finance and technology personnel
- Collaborated with second sales hire to implement new e-marketing campaigns and used video to reach leads

Breakthru Beverage Minnesota, Sales Consultant, Saint Paul, Minnesota

September 2013- April 2018

- Successfully maintaining and growing a territory of 99 accounts while growing annual revenue at 7% year over year
- Implemented persuasive selling techniques to grow business, through PowerPoint presentations and verbal pitches
- Successfully selling in the total beverage system with the responsibility of selling three major books of wine, beer and spirits amounting to 7,500 different products
- Self-starter that managed my own weekly schedule to ensure goals and deadlines are met

Warner Stellian, Sales Consultant, Woodbury, Minnesota

March 2011- September 2013

- Managed an open book of business of 1.5 million dollars a year, while meeting and exceeding company goals
- Worked in a commission only environment
- Worked with customer service as a team player to resolve customer issues
- Worked with operations to successfully deliver product according to customer needs

CERTIFICATIONS

- Hubspot Sales Certified
- Hubspot Inbound Marketing Certified
- HIPAA Compliant Certified